<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu on Coding Automaton</title>
    <link>http://jessezhuang.github.io/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu on Coding Automaton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 18:17:10 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jessezhuang.github.io/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualbox Tips for Ubuntu Guest in Windows Host</title>
      <link>http://jessezhuang.github.io/article/virtualbox-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 18:17:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jessezhuang.github.io/article/virtualbox-tips/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For Ubuntu tips, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://jessezhuang.github.io/
article/ubuntu/&#34;&gt;http://jessezhuang.github.io/
article/ubuntu/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-get-shared-folder-write-access&#34;&gt;How to Get Shared Folder Write Access&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When used as a virtual machine guest (Ubuntu 14.04LTS in Windows 10 host with Oracle VirtualBox), to get access to shared folder, run the following command in shell, replace &lt;code&gt;username&lt;/code&gt; with your ubuntu username.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;# replace username with your actual ubuntu username
$ sudo usermod -a -G vboxsf username
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, reboot the VM and you should have write access to the shared folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-create-virtualenv-in-shared-folder&#34;&gt;How to Create Virtualenv in Shared Folder&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating symbolic links in a VirtualBox shared folder is disabled, which will forbid you to create a virtualenv in a shared folder from the host machine. Simple test in terminal: &lt;code&gt;$ ln -s test&lt;/code&gt;, Either you&amp;rsquo;ll get a &lt;code&gt;failed to create symbolic link &#39;./testfile&#39;: Read-only file system&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Protocol error&lt;/code&gt;. Shutdown VM and close Virtualbox Manager in Windows host. Open an admin command prompt,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;C:\WINDOWS\system32&amp;gt;VBoxManage setextradata VM_name 
  VBoxInternal2/SharedFoldersEnableSymlinksCreate/shared_folder 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have not added virtualbox commands to your path, either do so or run &lt;code&gt;VBoxManage&lt;/code&gt; from the folder where it is located. Replace &lt;code&gt;VM_name&lt;/code&gt; with the name of the virtual machine,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.stack.imgur.com/NrMzq.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;vmname in virtualbox manager&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the name of &lt;code&gt;shared_folder&lt;/code&gt; with the name of the shared folder in the settings of your virtual machine,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.stack.imgur.com/yboaG.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shared folder name screenshot&#34; /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check the settings with the command below and should find one key about your shared folder indicating that it was enabled as in the second line below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;C:\WINDOWS\system32&amp;gt;vboxmanage getextradata ubuntu14-ppbdmmdd enumerate
Key: VBoxInternal2/SharedFoldersEnableSymlinksCreate/shared_folder, Value: 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that you still need to run the VirtualBox Manager as an administrator from Windows in order for the creation of virtualenv (symlinks) to work properly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>http://jessezhuang.github.io/article/ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 23:37:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jessezhuang.github.io/article/ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu version is 14.04 LTS running as a guest OS in Oracle VirtualBox 5. For VirtualBox related issues, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://jessezhuang.github.io/
article/virtualbox-tips/&#34;&gt;http://jessezhuang.github.io/
article/virtualbox-tips/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance-monitoring&#34;&gt;Performance Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;top&lt;/code&gt; from command line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;System Monitor&lt;/code&gt; application installed by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;screen-capture&#34;&gt;Screen Capture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application &lt;code&gt;Screenshot&lt;/code&gt; installed by default. Can take screenshot of whole screen, current window, or selected area. Similar to &amp;ldquo;Snipping Tool&amp;rdquo; in Windows. To run this tool from the shell, use &lt;code&gt;gnome-screeshot -i&lt;/code&gt; for interactive window specified with mouse, &lt;code&gt;gnome-screenshot -help&lt;/code&gt; for other options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lxde-desktop-environment&#34;&gt;LXDE Desktop Environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LXDE is a much lighter desktop environment (DE) and uses much less memory versus unityand is the standard DE in Lubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fix-lxde-pcmanfm-open-current-folder-in-terminal&#34;&gt;Fix LXDE PCMANFM Open Current Folder in Terminal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PCMANFM 1.2.0 is the default file manager used in LXDE which has a built in functionality to open a terminal window at the directory that you are currently browsing with a convenient shortcut of F4. It uses gnome terminal. The problem is the opened terminal window is totally black. The problem is the default profile is using black text on black background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the opened gnome terminal, select from menu bar Edit - Profile Preferences, Colors tab, uncheck &amp;ldquo;use colors from system theme&amp;rdquo;, select a built-in theme or your customized theme. I used white on black built-in theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With LXDE, the ubuntu 14.04LTS system is using about 240 Mb of ram at start up with pacmanfm using a little over 10 Mb. Comparing to unity, about 800 Mb of ram at start up with about 200 Mb for compiz. A lot of times compiz can ramp up to 500 Mb of ram. There is another option Openbox DE, the default is just a blank screen where you would have to right click to pop up the menu.The ram usage is a little less but you would have to customize the menu for it to be really user friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>